KARTHIKEYAN C (KC)

Core banking Technology Architect Infosys Limited (13.5 Years)

(65) 97843556 karthik1113job@gmail.com

PROFILE

Highly experienced professional in core banking product design. Proficient in architecting and managing core banking on public and hybrid cloud platforms. Excellent exposure on containerization of traditional monolithic applications and the art of choosing best fit for the given technology stack. Possesses extraordinary technical expertise, extensive problem-solving skills and ability to guide the team thoroughly in architecture, standards and coding.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Consulting and solutioning are the day to day activity on various technology related discussions. Engaging architects and stakeholders from DBS internally and solving both enterprise level and unit level technology roadmap related items in finacle. Actively participating in other platform and technology providers to DBS to fulfil product requirements.

Technology Architect & Solution consultant for DBS Bank Ltd	Infosys Limited - July 2014 onwards
Technology Project Lead.	Infosys Limited - May 2012 to Jun 2014
Product delivery lead at CFS , Manchester	Infosys Limited - Jun 2010 to May 2012
Software Engineer through Technology Analyst	Infosys Limited - Jan 2007 to May 2010

PRE-SALES EXPERIENCE

In addition to regular finacle core product implementation, as an architect of finacle to pre-sales,

- ☐ Bank of America Merrill Lynch: As solution architect represented the team of product and implementation for Bank of America Merrill lynch (BAML) and successfully won the deal for 16 country implementations of all modules of core banking.
- □ <u>DBS Paylah Wallet:</u> Architect for wallet solution under the brand of finacle. Executed 10 weeks of product alignment activities to finacle w.r.to specific wallet related gaps. Results awaited.
- ☐ **SIFL Singapore:** As technical solution architect demonstrated the on-prem capabilities of the banking product and won the deal and it is nearing the completion of the project.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in **Electronics and communication**. (First class honors)

Anna University, Chennai, India.

TECHNICAL SKILL			
	Hardcore C, C++ developer. Continuing JAVA, JS, few Python.		
	Proficiency in container related technologies Docker & Kubernetes .		
	Day in Day out with platforms Openshift, EKS and its ecosystem.		
	Expert in Core banking System design and its integrations.		
	Architecture solutions in AWS .		
CERTIFICATIONS			
	AWS Certified Solutions architect - Professional.		
	CNCF Certified Kubernetes administrator.		
RECOGNITIONS			
	Infosys GEM Awards 2012 for Finacle batch processing innovations		
	Infosys GEM Awards 2009 for Emirates NBD finacle v10.4 delivery.		
	Infosys Excellence Awards 2011 for CFS solution delivery.		
SUMMARY			
٥	Technical architect for complete design of Docker and Kubernetes based core banking applications of the first ever implementation of DBS.		
۵	Highly skilled CORE Banking System Architect with 13.5 years of experience in the IT/Banking including 6 years of Singapore experience and 2 years of Europe region.		
	Stability & Performance improvement Anchor. Technical Solution Consultant of core banking system and its bank wide interfaces.		
٠	Delivered more than 100 projects to DBS Bank Ltd as consultant and delivery lead with complete end to end responsibility till customer onboarding.		
٠	Enormous experience in Project Management caliber to drive the project efficiently by providing both business & technical solutions, efforts sizing and technical and design specifications for business initiatives and ensure the smooth operational rollout of projects.		
	Strong technical expertise as worked in both Product development & Implementation stages.		
	Well experienced professional in engaging different technology partners and regulatory bodies as part of project Implementation and Support.		
	Excellent problem-solving skills with strong Technical background & good interpersonal skills.		
	Experienced in managing large & multi-vendor project implementation.		